This video is longer than most of my videos. because the teaching is important.
这个视频比我的绝大多数视频都要长。因为这个教导很重要。
I want you to understand it well.
我希望你能很好地理解它。
What I will say will shock many people. You may think I have no faith in God.
我要说的话会让很多人震惊。你可能认为我对上帝没有信心。
But I must tell you what Jesus really said about miracles.
但我必须告诉你耶稣所说的真正的关于神迹的事。
First, I will show how we misunderstand the Bible by not listening closely.
首先，我要说明我们的不仔细聆听是如何误解圣经的。
I need to clear this up,so we can hear the truth about what Jesus said.
我需要澄清这一点，这样我们才能听到真正的耶稣所说的话。
Most of us read the Bible selfishly.
我们大多数人都自私地阅读圣经。
Listen to this verse from the Book of Acts: It is Peter preaching on the Day of Pentecost.
听听使徒行传中的这节经文：这是彼得在五旬节那天的讲道。
“This is what the prophet Joel predicted: God promised to give his Spirit to everyone.
使徒行传 2-16 这正是先知约珥所说的：使徒行传 2-17...我要将我的灵浇灌凡有血气的，
"Your children,” he said, "will prophesy. “Young men will see visions, and old men will dream dreams.”
“你们的儿女，”他说，“会说预言。 “少年人会见异象，老人会做异梦。”
“My servants and maids will receive my Spirit. They, too, will prophesy.”
“我的仆人和使女会领受我的灵。他们也会说预言。”
“I will show signs in heaven and on earth: Blood, and fire, and smoke.”
“我要在天上地下显出迹象：有血、有火、有烟雾。
When you hear that, do you feel like God gave his Spirit  to these thousands of people…
当你听到这些时，你是否觉得上帝将他的灵赐给了这成千上万的人……
…so that they would all be able  to do miraculous things?
……让他们都能行神迹？
It sounds like that, doesn’t it?
听起来是这样，不是吗？
But before we say too much, I want you to think…
但在我们说太多之前，我想让你想想……
Think of all those thousands of people (not counting the apostles).
想想那成千上万的人（不包括使徒）。
How many miracles can you  remember them doing?
你能记得他们行了多少神迹？
Any healings? It is not easy to think of any, is it?
有什么医治吗？很难想起来任何一个，是吗？
I’m thinking mostly of healings.
我想到的主要是医治。
Thousands of people talked in tongues. Many prophesied and preached.
成千上万的人用方言交谈。许多人预言并传道。
I’m thinking about the kind of miracles  that do not happen in churches today.
我在想今天在教堂里不会发生的那种神迹。
In I Corinthians 12, Paul said that not everyone can do miracles, and not everyone can heal people.
在哥林多前书 12 章，保罗说不是每个人都能行神迹，也不是每个人都能医治人。
In Acts 2:43 it says it was the apostles who did the miracles.
使徒行传 2:43 说是使徒行了神迹。
It does not say that anyone who was not an apostle, did miracles.
并没有说任何不是使徒的人都行过神迹。
Even at the time, no one believed  that everyone could do miracles.
即使在那个时候，也没有人相信每个人都能行神迹。
Only the apostles did them. We need to see that.
只有使徒这样做了。我们需要看到这一点。
Stop for a minute. I am not trying to change the truth.
先稍等片刻。我不是要改变真相。
I want us to see pieces of truth that we don’t like to see.
我希望我们能看到我们不喜欢看到的那些真相。
We want to believe they all did miracles; So we can, too.
我们想相信他们都行了神迹；那样我们就也可以。
That is our dream: That the Holy Spirit is all about miracles.
那是我们的梦想：圣灵就是一切关于神迹的东西。
More Holy Spirit equals bigger and better miracles.
更多的圣灵等于更大更好的神迹。
But that may not be true. Are you open to that being true?
但这可能不是真的。你愿意接受这个事实吗？
Maybe the apostles had more Holy Spirit, and it is why they did miracles.
也许使徒有更多的圣灵，这就是他们行神迹的原因。
Remember, the apostles did miracles.
请记住，使徒行了神迹。
Listen to what Paul the Apostle said in I Corinthians 2:4…
听听使徒保罗在哥林多前书 2:4 中所说的话……
My preaching was not with beautiful words, but with power from God’s Spirit.
哥林多前书 2-4 我说的话，讲的道，不是用智慧委婉的言语，乃是用圣灵和大能的明证，
It sounds like Paul was doing miracles in every city that he visited.
听起来像是保罗在他访问过的每个城市都在行神迹。
And people listened to him  because he did miracles.
人们听他，因为他行了神迹。
But we will do with Paul  what we did with the non-apostles:
但是我们会对保罗做我们对非使徒所做的事情：
How many miracles of Paul can you list?
你能列举出多少保罗的神迹？
Stop the video and make a list. How many can you remember?
停止视频并列出清单。你能记住几个？
Paul did miracles, but we don’t remember them, do we?
保罗行过神迹，但我们不记得他们，对吗？
I think he mostly did miracles  for emergencies and not for a show.
我认为他主要是为了紧急情况而不是为了表演而行神迹。
His real job was to preach.
他真正的工作是传道。
A snake bit him, and he was not hurt.
一条蛇咬了他，他没有受伤。
A man fell out of a high window and died.
一名男子从高窗坠下身亡。
Paul fell on him and hugged him, and then he told the people the man was not dead.
保罗扑在他身上并拥抱他，然后他告诉人们这个人并没有死。
In Acts 13, Paul made a man become blind.
在使徒行传 13 章，保罗使一个人瞎眼。
In Acts 14, Paul healed a crippled man.
在使徒行传 14 章，保罗医治了一个瘸腿的人。
In Acts 28, he healed Publius’ father.
在使徒行传 28 章，他医治了部百流的父亲。
He cast a demon out of a woman in Acts 16.
在使徒行传 16 章，他从一个女人身上赶出一个鬼。
In Acts 19 is a strange story.
在使徒行传 19 中有一个奇怪的故事。
Christians took Paul’s handkerchiefs  and gave them to sick people, who were healed.
基督徒拿了保罗的手帕，递给病人，病人痊愈了。
We don’t who, how, or when, but some people were healed without Paul being there.
我们不知道是谁，如何或何时，但有些人在没有保罗在场的情况下被治愈了。
That’s all we know about Paul and miracles.
这就是我们对保罗和神迹的全部了解。
It’s surprising that we don’t  know more than that.
令人惊讶的是，我们不知道的更多。
People do not think of miracles when they think of Paul.
人们一想到保罗就不会想到神迹。
Now for the other apostles.
现在是其他使徒。
Can we make a long list  of all their miracles?
我们可以列出他们所有的神迹吗？
Stop the video and make a list.
停止视频并列出清单。
Did you get the one about  the lame man in the temple?
你列出了圣殿里那个瘸腿的人吗？
Did you list any more?
你再列出来了吗？
It says in two places that Stephen, Phillip, and Barnabas did miracles, but that’s all.
它在两处说司提反、腓利和巴拿巴行了神迹，但仅此而已。
In Acts 9, Peter heals a man, and he brings Tabitha back to life.
在使徒行传第 9 章，彼得医治了一个人，他使大比大复活。
An earthquake opened a prison for Paul and Silas.
一场地震为保罗和西拉打开了监狱。
But they didn’t do the miracle themselves.
但他们自己并没有行神迹。
After the day of Pentecost, the Bible describes in detail less than ten miracles.
五旬节之后，圣经详细描述了不到十个神迹。
On the whole, The Book of Acts  is quiet about miracles.
总体而言，《使徒行传》对神迹保持沉默。
They happened, but little more is said about them.
它们发生了，但关于它们的说法很少。
We learn two lessons from this.
我们从中学到了两个教训。
1. God did miracles. They did not stop  after Jesus went to heaven.
1. 神行了神迹。耶稣升天后，他们并没有停止。
2. God still does miracles today. I have seen three or four  real miracles, myself.
2. 神今天仍然行神迹。我自己见过三四个真正的神迹。
I didn’t do them, but God did.
我没有这样做，但上帝做了。
Point one: God does miracles… Then, and now.
第一点：上帝行神迹......然后，现在。
But Point two is that  they were mostly secret.
但第二点是它们大多是秘密的。
They were not used to  preach sermons.
他们不曾讲道。
If a miracle happened or not was not important to most people.
神迹是否发生对大多数人来说并不重要。
Everyone was faithful, with or without a miracle.
无论有没有神迹，每个人都是信实的
This is most important today.
这是今天最重要的。
The Bible says that lying miracles will happen in the last days.
圣经说在末世会发生假神迹。
The Antichrist and the False Prophet will both be able to do miracles.
敌基督者和假先知都能够行神迹。
Smart magicians can copy almost any miracle.
聪明的魔术师几乎可以复制任何神迹。
We must find out if God wants us to do miracles...
我们必须弄清楚上帝是否希望我们行神迹……
…or if he has something  better for us.
……或者他有更好的东西给我们。
Maybe WE are the ones  who want to do miracles.
也许“我们”才是想要行神迹的人。
But we say that GOD wants us to do miracles.
但是我们说上帝要我们行神迹。
What we read in the New Testament, from people like Peter, James, and John, are teachings.
我们在新约中读到的 来自像彼得、雅各和约翰这样的人的教导。
And none of them teach about miracles.
他们都没有教导神迹。
Miracles happened, yes.But there was no big show and no teaching about them.
神迹发生了，是的。但是没有大秀，也没有关于这些的教导。
Please be patient with me. I will teach what Jesus taught soon.
请对我有点耐心。我很快就会教导耶稣所教导的。
I just want to get the bigger picture first.
我只是先看大局。
I will look at something I see in many letters that I receive.
我会看看我在收到的许多信件中看到的东西。
Some say they have done miracles. Others say they will do miracles.
有人说他们行了神迹。其他人说他们将要行神迹。
So I should listen to them.
所以我应该听他们的。
But what they say mostly takes me away from Jesus and just makes them special.
但他们所说的几乎是让我远离耶稣，并把他们变得特别。
Where does this thinking come from?
这种想法从何而来？
It comes from us thinking that miracles will build God’s kingdom.
它来自于我们认为神迹会建立上帝的国度。
People will listen  if we do miracles.
如果我们行神迹，人们会听。
So preachers say, “If you do this, you will get your miracles.”
所以传道人说：“如果你这样做，你就会得到神迹。”
They tell us to say a miracle happened when a miracle has not happened.
他们告诉我们，即使神迹没有发生，也要说神迹发生了。
They try to make themselves special... Better than all the other preachers.
他们试图让自己变得特别……比所有其他传道人都好。
Oral Roberts said that he had raised  20 people from the dead.
欧罗·罗伯茨说，他已经使 20 人从死里复活。
When pushed to prove it, he admitted he had not raised anyone from the dead.
当被要求证明这一点时，他承认他没有使任何人从死里复活。
Other preachers say  that angels talk to them.
其他传道人说天使对他们说话。
They teach them secrets that only they know.
他们教给他们只有他们知道的秘密。
Others say they went to heaven and they talked with God.
其他人说他们去了天堂并与上帝交谈。
And it works!
并且这样说很有效！
People love it.
人们喜欢它。
The bigger the lie, the more who will come to listen.
谎言越大，来听的人就越多。
But in the Book of Acts it was the opposite.
但在使徒行传中，情况正好相反。
A lot of miracles happened.
发生了很多神迹。
But the right hand did not know what the left hand did.
但是右手不知道左手做了什么。
From our study of the Book of Acts we know they did not talk about it.
从我们对使徒行传的研究我们知道他们没有谈论它。
But in the gospels, hundreds of miracles happened.
但在福音书中，发生了数百个神迹。
And there are stories of dozens of separate miracles.
还有几十个独立的神迹的故事。
At times, Jesus healed  everyone who came to him.
有时，耶稣会医治每个来到他面前的人。
Jesus said his followers would do even better things than he did.
耶稣说他的门徒会做比他做的更大的事。
Some verses sound like Jesus did many miracles, and  he wants us to do the same thing.
有些经文听起来像是耶稣行了许多神迹，他希望我们也做同样的事。
Why are we not doing them?
为什么我们不做呢？
Not enough faith is part of it.
没有足够的信心是其中的一部分。
But why did the early Christians not do more miracles?
但是为什么早期的基督徒没有多行神迹呢？
Some preachers say they  are doing many miracles.
有些传道人说他们正在行许多神迹。
They say God will do miracles for you, if you just tell him to do miracles.
他们说上帝会为你行神迹，只要你告诉他行神迹。
"Say it, and get it," they say.
“说出来，得到它，”他们说。
But none will go through a hospital and cure even half of the patients.
但不会有人会经过一家医院，就能治愈甚至一半的病人。
The truth is that miracles  mostly do not happen today.
事实上，神迹在今天大多不会发生。
Those who say they can do miracles usually turn out to be exaggerating.
那些说他们可以行神迹的人通常被证明是夸大其词。
Jesus did many miracles. But if it was to show off…
耶稣行了许多神迹。但如果是为了炫耀……
...why did he tell so many people to keep it secret?
……他为什么要告诉这么多人保密？
Is that how today’s preachers do it?
今天的传道人是这样作的吗？
If Jesus was against showing off, then why did he do miracles?
如果耶稣反对炫耀，那他为什么要行神迹呢？
In Matthew 20:34  Jesus meets 3 blind men.
在马太福音 20:34 耶稣遇见了三个瞎子。
It says, “Jesus loved them, and he touched their eyes.
经上说：“耶稣爱他们，摸他们的眼睛。
“They were healed, and they followed him.”
“他们痊愈了，就跟从了他。”
Jesus loved people.
耶稣爱人。
The Bible says Jesus loved the multitudes.
圣经说耶稣爱众人。
He loved a widow whose son had died. He loved a blind man.
他爱一个死了儿子的寡妇。他爱一个盲人。
Jesus told a story when asked how to live forever:
当被问及如何永生时，耶稣关于爱神爱邻舍讲了一个故事：
"A Samaritan saw an injured man and he loved him.
“一个撒玛利亚人看到一个受伤的人，就爱他。
“He put medicine on the wounds and bandaged him.
“他在伤口上涂药并包扎。
“He put him on his donkey and took him to a hotel and cared for him."
“他把他放在驴子上，带他去旅馆照顾他。”
Both stories talk about healing. Both say healing comes from love.
两个故事都在谈论医治。两者都说医治来自爱。
They are not trying  to prove anything.
他们不想证明任何事情。
The Samaritan does not do a miracle.
撒玛利亚人不会行神迹。
How does that go together with the miracles that Jesus did?
这与耶稣所行的神迹有什么关系？
Jesus had infinite power.
耶稣有无限的能力。
Everything that was made  was made by him.
被造的一切都是靠他所造的。
If the Creator of the world is here on Earth as a human…
如果世界的创造者作为人类来到地球上……
What would he do if he loved someone?
如果他爱一个人，他会怎么做？
He healed!
他医治了对方！
Just as naturally as did the Good Samaritan.
就像好撒玛利亚人一样自然。
When Jesus felt love, his touch was miraculous.
当耶稣感受到爱时，他的触摸是神迹般的。
But he compliments and does not criticise...
但他是肯定而不是批评
...the one who used medicine: Alcohol, and oil.
...使用药物的人：酒和油。
Jesus says that this nursing care is a good example of what it takes to receive eternal life.
耶稣说这种照顾是一个很好的例子关于如果获得永生。
Why?
为什么？
Because it came from a heart of love.
因为它来自一颗爱的心。
NOW…
现在…
What did Jesus teach about miracles?
耶稣对神迹有什么教导？
Maybe you will understand it better now. It is a little shocking.
也许你现在会更好地理解它。这有点令人震惊。
The same teaching is repeated two times In Matthew 12 and in Matthew 16.
同样的教导在马太福音 12 章和马太福音 16 章重复了两次。
Jesus said an evil and unfaithful world wants miracles.
耶稣说一个邪恶和淫乱的世界想要神迹。
But they will not receive a miracle. Apart from the miracle of Jonah.
但他们不会得到神迹。除了约拿的神迹。
Like so many teachings of Jesus,  they hide this one too.
就像耶稣的许多教导一样，他们也隐藏了这一点。
Pentecostals are not the only ones who hide the truth about miracles.
五旬节派并不是唯一隐瞒神迹真相的人。
Catholics and Pentecostals both measure spirituality by miracles.
天主教徒和五旬节教徒都通过神迹来衡量灵性。
To be a Saint in the Catholic Church, you must do at least one miracle.
要成为天主教会的圣人，您必须至少行一个神迹。
They say that sticks and stones  and statues do magical healings.
他们说棍棒、石头和雕像有神奇的治疗作用。
Like the miracle waters of Lourdes.
就像卢尔德的神迹之水。
Statues that cry, and sores that never go away…
哭泣的雕像和永不消退的疮……
Are all used to say that God  is in their church.
都习惯说上帝在他们的教会里。
Catholics could teach Pentecostals a few things!
天主教徒可以教五旬节派一些东西！
But what did Jesus say is behind  all of this?
但耶稣说这一切的背后是什么？
Say it: An evil and unfaithful world.
说吧：一个邪恶和淫乱的世界。
Do you believe that?
你相信吗？
Do you believe Jesus?
你相信耶稣吗？
Do you see why I said this teaching is hard to believe?
你明白我为什么说这个教导令人难以置信吗？
Again:  Miracles happen!
我们再说：神迹发生了！
But God is the Boss. It is his choice.
但上帝是老板。这是他的选择。
Only an evil and unfaithful world  thinks miracles will fix the world.
只有邪恶和淫乱的世界才会认为神迹会修复世界。
The second half of Jesus’ teaching will help us to understand.
耶稣教导的后半部分将帮助我们理解。
An evil world will only receive the miracle of Jonah.
一个邪恶的世界只有约拿的神迹。
Jonah was inside a whale for three days like Jesus was buried for three days..
约拿在一条鲸鱼里待了三天，就像耶稣被埋葬了三天一样。
Is that the miracle  that the world will receive?
难道这就是世界将有的神迹？
How can we make today’s evil world  believe that Jesus arose from the dead?
我们如何让今天的邪恶世界相信耶稣从死里复活？
The real question is this: Do WE believe it?
真正的问题是：我们相信吗？
Jonah never told Nineveh about his miracle.
约拿从未告诉尼尼微他的神迹。
He did not do a miracle for the people of Nineveh.
他没有为尼尼微人行神迹。
He just told them the truth.
他只是告诉了他们真理。
Change or die! That’s it.
改变或死亡！而已。
That is what we must say. They are headed for hell.
这是我们必须说的。他们正走向地狱。
Inside the church, and outside of it…
教堂里面，外面……
We are living in an evil  and unfaithful world.
我们生活在一个邪恶和淫乱的世界。
There will be NO  miracles on demand.
不会有按着我们要求的神迹。
Not any that we can tell people about.
我们没有任何可以告诉人们的。
The miracle was just between Jonah and God.
神迹只在约拿和上帝之间。
This is the same as what we have learned by looking at miracles in the New Testament.
这与我们通过查看新约中的神迹所学到的相同。
Miracles happen! But you don’t talk about them.
神迹发生！但你不谈论他们。
And they only happen for people who will obey Jesus with or without a miracle.
它们只会发生在那些无论有没有神迹都会服从耶稣的人身上。
Jesus tells us to go and preach. The miracles will “follow”.
耶稣告诉我们去传道。神迹会“跟随”。
“Follow” means they don’t happen until after we start obeying.
“跟随”意味着它们不会开始，直到我们开始顺服。
And it says nothing about  us controlling the miracles.
它没有说我们控制神迹。
God does as he chooses. If we disagree, then we are  part of what group?
上帝按他的选择行事。如果我们不同意，那么我们属于哪个群体？
The evil, unfaithful world that we now live in.
我们现在生活的 邪恶、淫乱的世界。
It will not be easy for those who have believed for years that it is all about miracles.
对于多年来一直相信这一切都是有关于神迹的人来说，这并不容易。
Jesus says that thinking comes from: An evil and unfaithful world.
耶稣说思想来自：一个邪恶和淫乱的世界。
Pastors who make a show of such things Sunday after Sunday…
牧师们一个星期天又一个星期天的展示这种事情……
Are apostles of what? An evil and unfaithful world.
他们是什么的使徒？一个邪恶和淫乱的世界的。
Leave them! Let them go to hell without you.
离开他们！不要跟他们一直走向灭亡。
And let them take their  lying miracles with them.
让他们随身带着他们的谎言神迹一起。
They will never teach you to obey Jesus.
他们永远不会教你顺服耶稣。
Every one of those miracle men is a false apostle.
这些神迹人中的每一个都是假使徒。
The voice of an evil and unfaithful world.
邪恶和淫乱的世界的声音。
Leave them and turn to Jesus before they take you to hell.
在他们带你下地狱之前，离开他们转向耶稣。
That is where they are going if they will not turn to Jesus.
如果他们不转向耶稣，那就是他们要去的地方。
Many of you don’t like hearing this.
你们中的许多人不喜欢听到这个。
But if you can hear it, you will start to grow as God wants you to grow.
但如果你能听到它，你就会开始成长，就像上帝希望你成长。
Please pray about it.
请为此祷告。
Drop the false hope of miracles, and hold to Jesus with both hands.
放弃神迹的虚假盼望，双手抱住耶稣。
Before I finish, I will look at something that I said near the start of this video.
在我结束之前，我将看一下我在视频开头所说的内容。
Jesus said his followers will do better things that he did.
耶稣说他的追随者会做得比他做得更大。
This promise says we can do something  better than raising Lazarus from the dead.
这个应许说我们可以做一些比让拉撒路从死里复活更大的事情。
How can we do better than that?
我们怎样才能做得更大？
Think about this: Did Lazarus still die in the end? And did he stay dead that time?
想一想：拉撒路最后还是死了吗？那时他死了吗？
Anyone raised from the dead in the Bible, apart from when Jesus came back to life…
圣经中任何从死里复活的人，除了耶稣复活的时候……
Was only for a few years.
只是让多活几年而已，玛门往往也能。
The one thing better than  being raised to life for a few years…
比被复活几年更好的一件事......
…is to give someone eternal life.
……是给某人永生。
I will say it again.  Think about it:
我再说一遍。想想看：
The only thing better than being raised to life for a few years…
唯一比复活几年更好的事情......
…is being raised to life forever.
……复活到永远。
Now, look at I Corinthians 12.
现在，请看哥林多前书 12 章。
Paul says there are many  different gifts in the church.
保罗说教会中有许多不同的恩赐。
Healing and miracles were, to Paul, two very different gifts.
对保罗来说，医治和神迹是两种截然不同的恩赐。
So maybe the Good Samaritan had  a non-miraculous gift of healing.
所以也许好撒玛利亚人有一种非神迹般的医治恩赐。
He poured oil and wine into the wound. He had the gift of healing.
他把油和酒倒在伤口上。他有医治的恩赐。
At the end of I Corinthians 12, Paul says,  “I will show you something better.”
在哥林多前书 12 章的结尾，保罗说：“我要给你看更大的东西，最妙的东西。”
Here it is!  A better way.   Better than miracles!
这里是！更大。比各样恩赐更妙！
Better than tongues! Even better than prophecy!
胜过方言！甚至比预言更好！
That is the start to the wonderful “love chapter” of I Corinthians 13.
这就是哥林多前书 13 章美妙的“爱的篇章”的开始。
“If I speak in tongues and do not have love, I am just making noise.  Nothing more.
“如果我说方言而没有爱，我只是在制造噪音。而已。
He then says that all the gifts of God, whether miraculous or not…
然后他说上帝的所有恩赐，无论是否神奇……
Are like looking through a cloudy mirror when you see this better way.
相比于你看到的这种更好的方式，那些就像透过模糊的镜子在看，
The better way is love. God’s supernature love.
更好的方式是爱。神超自然的爱。
Christ loved like that.
基督那样的爱。
But he wants us to  show the world that love too.
但他也希望我们向世界展示那爱。
Not the miracles of an evil, unfaithful world, but God’s real answer to our problems.
不是邪恶、淫乱的世界的神迹，而是上帝对我们问题的真正答案。
Love! The strength of God to change us.
爱！神改变我们的力量。
That’s it. I’ll leave it there.
而已。我会把它留在那里。
You can hear more about this in my video Named “The Greatest Rule”.
您可以在我名为“最伟大的规则”的视频中了解更多相关信息。
I hope to hear from you, and encourage you to grow in Jesus.
我希望听到你的声音，并鼓励你在耶稣里成长。
Please write to me. And share this video with others.
请写信给我。并与他人分享此视频。
Thank you for listening. God bless you.
谢谢你的聆听。上帝祝福你。